<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/phys_s12_blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/phys_s12_blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-06-25T15:34:20-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/phys_s12_blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Blas Kozicki PHYS S-12 2023 Blog</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Laser cutting: visiting Paris with cardboard</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/phys_s12_blog/2023/06/24/week2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Laser cutting: visiting Paris with cardboard" /><published>2023-06-24T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-06-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/phys_s12_blog/2023/06/24/week2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/phys_s12_blog/2023/06/24/week2.html">&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-xl underline&quot;&gt;Concept&lt;/h2&gt; 
&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p link&quot;&gt;Laser cutting is an extremely useful technique to cut simple materials, such as cardboard. This week, we learnt how to operate a laser cutter and we were assigned to create a press-fit construction. To accomplish this, I decided to use a CAD software called Fusion360. I already had experience using it, and the only way to do parametric accurate modeling in the other software option, Blender, is by using the addon &lt;a class=&quot;link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cadsketcher.com/&quot;&gt;CAD Sketcher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;





&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;This site was created with the help of a static site generator: &lt;strong&gt;Jekyll&lt;/strong&gt;. Static site generators are really useful when content looks similar, which is exactly the case of a blog. That is why I decided to use Jekyll for this project. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;To style the site, I&apos;m using &lt;a href=&quot;https://tailwindcss.com&quot; class=&quot;text-blue-400 underline&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;TailwindCSS&lt;/a&gt;, which a css framework that is extremely useful for rapidly building a good-looking website. It works pretty much like a modern version of bootstrap. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;I think that the most interesting development choice of this project is using &lt;strong&gt;Github Actions&lt;/strong&gt; to compile and deploy the website. I had never used Github Actions, but there are many useful ressources only to learn how to use them. They can be extremely useful to automate things such as, in this case, the Jekyll build of my website. You&apos;ll find bellow a picture of what an &quot;action&quot; looks like. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/githubactions.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of a Github Action&quot;&gt;


&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-xl mt-[30px] underline&quot;&gt;Final Project Idea #1&lt;/h2&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;My first idea for the final project is to design a &lt;strong&gt;thrust vector control mount &lt;/strong&gt; (TVC) for model rockets. TVC allows rockets to change the direction of its thrust, and therefore its flight trajectory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;mb-p&quot; href=&quot;https://bps.space/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/tvcexample.jpg&quot; class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;p class=&quot;text-sm&quot;&gt;3D model of a TVC mount made by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/@BPSspace&quot; class=&quot;link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;bps.space&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To achieve a successfull project, I would need to succesfully develop a gimbal capable of holding a model rocket thruster, and a flight computer capable of detecting the orientation of the rocket (and therefore corret the trajectory).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-xl mt-[30px] underline&quot;&gt;Final Project Idea #2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My second final project idea is to design and build a &lt;strong&gt;3D printed RC car&lt;/strong&gt;. This project would require a lot of material testing (to make sure the different parts of the car are strong enough to sustain high speeds), and a lot of research to find the right components. 
    That is I&apos;m more inclined to pursue my first idea, which would only require simple components (such as servos).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/rccarexample.jpg&quot; class=&quot;inline mt-5&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;text-sm&quot;&gt;Example of a 3d printed car made by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r2UDc4A8huY&quot; class=&quot;text-blue-400 underline&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Engineering Nonsense&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Concept Laser cutting is an extremely useful technique to cut simple materials, such as cardboard. This week, we learnt how to operate a laser cutter and we were assigned to create a press-fit construction. To accomplish this, I decided to use a CAD software called Fusion360. I already had experience using it, and the only way to do parametric accurate modeling in the other software option, Blender, is by using the addon CAD Sketcher</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Website creation and final project ideas</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/phys_s12_blog/2023/06/21/week1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Website creation and final project ideas" /><published>2023-06-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-06-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/phys_s12_blog/2023/06/21/week1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/phys_s12_blog/2023/06/21/week1.html">&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-xl underline&quot;&gt;Website technology&lt;/h2&gt; 
&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;This site was created with the help of a static site generator: &lt;strong&gt;Jekyll&lt;/strong&gt;. Static site generators are really useful when content looks similar, which is exactly the case of a blog. That is why I decided to use Jekyll for this project. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;To style the site, I&apos;m using &lt;a href=&quot;https://tailwindcss.com&quot; class=&quot;link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;TailwindCSS&lt;/a&gt;, which a css framework that is extremely useful for rapidly building a good-looking website. It works pretty much like a modern version of bootstrap. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;I think that the most interesting development choice of this project is using &lt;strong&gt;Github Actions&lt;/strong&gt; to compile and deploy the website. I had never used Github Actions, but there are many useful ressources online to learn how to use them. This Github feature allows you to quickly setupt actions to do things such as, in this case, automate the Jekyll build of my website. You&apos;ll find bellow a picture of what an &quot;action&quot; looks like. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/githubactions.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of a Github Action&quot;&gt;


&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-xl mt-[30px] underline&quot;&gt;Final Project Idea #1&lt;/h2&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;My first idea for the final project is to design a &lt;strong&gt;thrust vector control (TVC) &lt;/strong&gt; mount for model rockets. TVC allows rockets to change the direction of its thrust, and therefore its flight trajectory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;mb-p&quot; href=&quot;https://bps.space/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/tvcexample.jpg&quot; class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;p class=&quot;text-sm&quot;&gt;3D model of a TVC mount made by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/@BPSspace&quot; class=&quot;text-blue-400 underline&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;bps.space&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To achieve a successfull project, I would need to succesfully develop a gimbal capable of holding a model rocket thruster, and a flight computer capable of detecting the orientation of the rocket (and therefore corret the trajectory).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-xl mt-[30px] underline&quot;&gt;Final Project Idea #2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My second final project idea is to design and build a &lt;strong&gt;3D printed RC car&lt;/strong&gt;. This project would require a lot of material testing (to make sure the different parts of the car are strong enough to sustain high speeds), and a lot of research to find the right components. 
    That is I&apos;m more inclined to pursue my first idea, which would only require simple components (such as servos).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/rccarexample.jpg&quot; class=&quot;inline mt-5&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;text-sm&quot;&gt;Example of a 3d printed car made by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r2UDc4A8huY&quot; class=&quot;text-blue-400 underline&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Engineering Nonsense&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Website technology This site was created with the help of a static site generator: Jekyll. Static site generators are really useful when content looks similar, which is exactly the case of a blog. That is why I decided to use Jekyll for this project. To style the site, I&apos;m using TailwindCSS, which a css framework that is extremely useful for rapidly building a good-looking website. It works pretty much like a modern version of bootstrap. I think that the most interesting development choice of this project is using Github Actions to compile and deploy the website. I had never used Github Actions, but there are many useful ressources online to learn how to use them. This Github feature allows you to quickly setupt actions to do things such as, in this case, automate the Jekyll build of my website. You&apos;ll find bellow a picture of what an &quot;action&quot; looks like.</summary></entry></feed>