<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/phys_s12_blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/phys_s12_blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-07-15T18:04:33-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/phys_s12_blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Blas Kozicki PHYS S-12 2023 Blog</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">3D Scanning and Printing, legos!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/phys_s12_blog/2023/07/12/week5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="3D Scanning and Printing, legos!" /><published>2023-07-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-07-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/phys_s12_blog/2023/07/12/week5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/phys_s12_blog/2023/07/12/week5.html">&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-xl underline&quot;&gt;3D Scanning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;3D CAD can be very useful to &lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;accurately design&lt;/span&gt; things, but trying to replicate a
  &lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;complex real-world shape
  &lt;/span&gt; can be quite challenging. 3D scanning is a very useful technology which can create a 3D model of a physical
  model by scanning it using many different techniques. In our lab, there is a &lt;a href=&quot;www.revopoint3d.com&quot;
    class=&quot;link&quot;&gt;RevoPoint scanner&lt;/a&gt;, which is (supposedly) very accurate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;The software to control the camera has a &quot;body&quot; option, so I naturally started by trying to 3D scan my
  face (who wouldn&apos;t?). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;w-[50%] mb-p&quot; src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/3dfacescan.jpg&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;My main face traits were fairly detailed, but the camera really struggled with my hair (which makes
  sense honestly). After trying to scan my whole face multiple times, I gave up, as I was not willing to shave my hair
  to have a good result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt; While I was looking through random things in the lab, I found a box filled with Lego pieces. Ever since
  I was a kid, I&apos;ve loved Lego. Here&apos;s a short stop-motion clip I made when I was 12 years old: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;w-[50%] mb-p&quot; src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/stopmotion.gif&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;There was this really interesting skeleton Horse, which had a cool shape that would be really hard to
  replicate with CAD, so I decided to scan it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;w-[50%] mb-p&quot; src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/legohorse.jpg&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;There&apos;s a small rotating base in the lab that is really useful to scan objects, as it rotates them in a
  slow and consistent way so that the scanner can keep track of the object and at the same time get measurements from
  every side of it. It is possible to do it by hand, by moving the camera around the object, but I don&apos;t recommend it
  because the camera can very easly loose track of the object, and once that happens it&apos;s extremely hard for it to
  &quot;retrack&quot; the object. This problem happened to me more that once, and I was forced to restart the scan each time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;w-[50%]&quot; src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/3dscansetup.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p italic text-right w-[50%] text-base&quot;&gt;Picture of the setup I used to scan the lego horse&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;The result of the scan is called a &lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;cloud point&lt;/span&gt;, which as its name implies, is a
  cloud of points, and not a 3D model. The result therefore has to be processed to be converted to a 3d mesh (.stl file
  for example). The RevoPoint software has many options to edit the result, which I used mainly to remove small floating
  meshes. But other than that, the output file is ready to use to either view it in your computer, or &lt;strong&gt;3D print
    it&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;w-[50%] mb-p2&quot; src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/3dscanresult.png&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-xl underline&quot;&gt;3D Printing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The thing I was most looking forward to this week was &lt;strong&gt;3D printing&lt;/strong&gt;. This fabrication
  method is what I intend to use to build a big chunck of my final project. There are two main types manufacturing: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;list-disc mb-p ml-[5%]&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;Substractive manufacturing&lt;/span&gt;: raw material is cut to produce a desired shape and size&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;Additive manufacturing&lt;/span&gt;: material is joined/deposited/solidified by (generally) a machine
    layer by layer, such as 3D printers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;The lab has quite a few Prusa MK3 printers,
  which are very capable and can print medium-sized objects. Although they are not very fast, the result is definitely
  worth the waiting. The worflow to use them is as easy as exporting a 3D model as a mesh, &quot;&lt;span
    class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;slicing&lt;/span&gt;&quot; it with the help of a slicing software (such as &lt;a
    href=&quot;https://www.prusa3d.com/page/prusaslicer_424/&quot; class=&quot;link&quot;&gt;Prusa Slicer&lt;/a&gt;), and sending the &lt;span
    class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;gcode&lt;/span&gt; (set of instructions) to the printer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;w-[50%]&quot; src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/3dexport.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p italic text-right w-[50%] text-base&quot;&gt;Exporting the 3D model as a mesh to the slicer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;The slicer&apos;s job is to generate a file containing all the places the printer has to go, based on your 3D
  mesh. It therefore needs to know exactly what printer you&apos;re using, what material (PLA in my case), and a lot of other
  things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;Some objects have big slopes that impossible to print, because it&apos;s not possible to print in mid-air.
  That is what &lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;supports&lt;/span&gt; are for. They provide a surface for the printer to put material, and
  then are easly removable once the print is done (or at least they are supposed to be...). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;w-[45%] mr-[2.5%] inline-block&quot; src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/slicing.gif&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;w-[45%] inline-block&quot; src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/slicingsupports.gif&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p inline-block italic text-right w-[45%] mr-[2.5%] text-base&quot;&gt;Slicer with no supports enabled&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p inline-block italic text-right w-[45%] text-base&quot;&gt;Slicer with default supports enabled&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;The slicer also tells you how long the print will take, and how much material it will use. You can find
  the time required for this print in the image below. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;w-[50%] mb-p&quot; src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/slicertimes.png&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;The next day I went to the lab to see the result, and found myself with a black plastic brick. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;w-[50%] mb-p&quot; src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/finishedprint.jpg&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;The support was &lt;strong&gt;extremely&lt;/strong&gt; hard to remove. It took me more than one hour with the
  help of a small screw driver to get rid of it. It was so difficult to remove the support, and I had to do so much
  force, that two of the breaks of the horse unfortunatly broke. This first print served me as a lesson to &lt;span
    class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;always test different orientations when slicing&lt;/span&gt; the model, as I could&apos;ve probably used a lot let
  supports if I had printed it side-ways, intead of upright. Nevertheless, the result was actually much better than I
  expected, but of course had some errors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;w-[50%] mb-p&quot; src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/horseresult.jpg&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;I am definitely very happy with the results, but most I importantly learned a lot of useful and
  interesting things, which I am sure will use in my final project.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">3D Scanning</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Electronics and Tools&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;(or how to build a Mini-Fountain)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/phys_s12_blog/2023/07/05/week3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Electronics and Tools&amp;lt;/br&amp;gt;(or how to build a Mini-Fountain)" /><published>2023-07-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-07-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/phys_s12_blog/2023/07/05/week3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/phys_s12_blog/2023/07/05/week3.html">&lt;script src=&quot;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/google/code-prettify@master/loader/run_prettify.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-xl underline&quot;&gt;Idea and objectives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;This week we learned about &lt;strong&gt;Motors&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Electronics&lt;/strong&gt;, and
  &lt;strong&gt;Microcontrollers&lt;/strong&gt;. To create something using all of those new concepts, I decided to create a water
  fountain. I knew from the begining it wasn&apos;t going to be an easy task, but I encountered a lot more problems than I
  initially expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;font-bold&quot;&gt;The main challenges of this project are: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;ml-[5%] mb-p list-disc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fabricating a watertight container&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Controlling and using a water pump&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ataching the different parts of the project (water container, pump, electronics, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;I started by drawing some sketches. I drew a boat-like shape, and a small structure on top of it which
  holds a small water pump (which I had found in the lab last week). I added some dimensions to have an idea of how the
  thing would actually look, and then modeled it with Fusion360.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/fountainsketch.jpg&quot; class=&quot;inline-block mr-[2.5%] mb-p w-[45%]&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/fountaincad.png&quot; class=&quot;inline-block w-[45%]&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/fountaincad.gif&quot; class=&quot;w-[50%] mx-auto&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;w-[50%] mx-auto hl text-center mb-p&quot;&gt;Click to download the &lt;a class=&quot;link&quot;
    href=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/stl/MiniFountain.f3d&quot;&gt;.f3d File&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;The main idea is to have an &lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;acrylic base&lt;/span&gt; (with a boat-like shape) that can serve
  as a water container. A secondary &lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;smaller base&lt;/span&gt; would hold a &lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;water pump&lt;/span&gt;
  in place, along with all the required electronics (&lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;esp32, batteries, motor driver&lt;/span&gt;). The two
  bases will be attached with &lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;two aluminum rods&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;M6 screws&lt;/span&gt; (more on
  that later). &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;iframe class=&quot;mb-p2&quot; src=&quot;https://icloud83866.autodesk360.com/shares/public/SHd38bfQT1fb47330c994103620c2994fc57?mode=embed&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;  frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-xl mt-[30px] underline&quot;&gt;Prototyping&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;After finishing the CAD model, I laser-cutted the whole thing with cardboard to make sure everything
  would fit correctly, as I didn&apos;t want to waste acrylic. It was important to test if the water pump holder fitted, if
  the container dimension&apos;s were decent, and have a rough idea of how the fountain would look in real life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;w-[45%] inline-block mb-p mr-[2.5%]&quot; src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/fountainprotopieces.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;w-[45%] inline-block mb-p&quot; src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/fountainprotoholder.jpg&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;I then decided to use a highly advanced chemical compound to join all the pieces together: &lt;span
    class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;hot glue&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;w-[50%] mb-p&quot; src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/fountainproto.jpg&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;The next step was to join the two &quot;bases&quot;. As I said earlier, we are going to use aluminum rods. The
  problem is that the lab only had very long aluminum rods. I therefore had to cut one in half to create two smaller
  ones using a hand saw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;w-[50%] mb-p&quot; src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/fountainrods.jpg&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;The next challenge was to figure out how to attach the rods to the top-base (which holds the water pump
  and the electronics). Last week we were taught how to thread the inside of a hole, and the rods I&apos;m using happen to be
  hollow, so I used a M6 screw drill tip to thread the end of each aluminum rod. Finding a fitting screw was quite a
  challenge, and I ended up switching to the imperial system to find an appropiate screw (I basically went through every
  single screw in the lab to find the right one).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;w-[50%] mb-p&quot; src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/fountainbaserods.jpg&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-xl mt-[30px] underline&quot;&gt;Final build&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;I laser-cutted the structure in acrylic, clamped it together, and glued it with epoxy. After waiting
  approximately 30 minutes, I glued the &quot;ramp&quot; to the rest of the structure, which was impossible to do before the rest
  of the structure was glued together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;w-[50%] mb-p&quot; src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/fountainclamps.jpg&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;After assembling everything, I realized that due to a pretty low contact surface, it was not going to be
  possible to glue the two aluminum rods to the base using epoxy. This is the kind of thing that I should&apos;ve planned
  beforehand, but because my lack of experience, didn&apos;t think of. I ultimately decided to drill two holes through the
  base of the fountain (which was extremly hard to do, mainly because of clamping issues) and attach the rods using
  screws. After threading the inside of the rods again, which was a really tedious task, I was finally able to attach
  the rods. All in all, this problem was a big setback with delayed the project more than I expected. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;The next step is to assemble all the electronics. &lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;3 AA batteries&lt;/span&gt; are connected
  to the 5V (4.5V in total, 1.5V each battery) and GND pins of an &lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;ESP32&lt;/span&gt;, aswell as the VCC and
  GND pins of a motor driver (I used the &lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;L9110&lt;/span&gt;). The ESP32 is connected to the A-IA pin of the
  motor driver (&lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;make sure the esp32 pin supports PWM, I used pin 12&lt;/span&gt;), which controls the speed
  of the motor. The motor driver is then connected to the water pump using two terminals and the wires that come with
  the motor. To easly manage power, I used solder to add two extra outputs to the batteries. This was necessary because
  as we just discussed, &lt;strong&gt;two&lt;/strong&gt; components need both VCC and GND inputs. To keep things simple (and mainly
  due to a lack of time), I zip tied all the components. Before assembling the components, I quickly threw together a
  schematic in Eagle (fusion360) to have an idea of what the electronics would roughly look like (see image below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;inline-block w-[45%] mr-[2.5%] mb-p&quot; src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/fountainschematic.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;inline-block w-[45%] mb-p&quot; src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/fountainelectronics.jpg&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;The final thing we need to do to have a working fountain, is to program our microcontroller. I will use
  the arduino programming language. I wrote a simple program that varies the speed of the pump over time using a sine
  wave, and uploaded it to the esp32 to finally test the water fountain. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class=&quot;code prettyprint&quot;&gt;

#define A1A 12  // pin 12 is defined for A1A, which controls the speed of the motor

void setup() {
  pinMode(A1A, OUTPUT);
}

void loop() {
  runMotor(A1A, 180, 255);
  delay(1);
}

// Variables for calculations regarding motor speed
float value;
float interpolatedValue;

// Function that drives motor with a speed interpolated from &apos;min&apos; to &apos;max&apos; using a sine wave
// Inputs: pin, minimumSpeed (0-255), maximumSpeed (0-255)
void runMotor(int pin, int min, int max) {
  value = sin(millis() / 1000.0);
  interpolatedValue = map(abs(value * 100), 0, 100, min, max);
  analogWrite(pin, 255 - interpolatedValue);
}

&lt;/pre&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">3D Modeling Household Objects</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/phys_s12_blog/2023/06/26/week25.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="3D Modeling Household Objects" /><published>2023-06-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-06-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/phys_s12_blog/2023/06/26/week25</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/phys_s12_blog/2023/06/26/week25.html">&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-xl underline&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1)&lt;/strong&gt; Modeling a lamp&lt;/h2&gt; 

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;The first household object I decided to model was a lamp. My goal is to succesfully model a good-looking lamp without using any tutorials, and therefore test my 3D modeling skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;I started modeling the base, which I made with 2 circles (one with a fixed diameter of &lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;120 mm&lt;/span&gt;, and the other with a fixed offset of &lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;-12.5 mm&lt;/span&gt;). I also added a smaller circle off-center, which is where the arm of the lamp will come out of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/lampModel/step1.png&quot; class=&quot;mb-p w-[50%]&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;I then extruded the outer circle &lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;30 mm&lt;/span&gt; and the inner circle (without the off-centered circle) &lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;20 mm&lt;/span&gt;. To make it look better, I used a fillet with a &lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;rolling ball corner type&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/lampModel/step2.png&quot; class=&quot;mb-p2 w-[50%]&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p italic&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;font-bold&quot;&gt;Side note: &lt;/span&gt; Adding appearances to 3D models can make them look a lot better (even if it&apos;s just a visual thing, it can make modeling much more pleasing). You will find bellow a picture of that same base with a wood appearance, and you&apos;ll notice that it looks a lot better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/lampModel/step2wood.png&quot; class=&quot;mb-p2 w-[50%]&quot;&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;I then started to work on the arm. I started by sketching a &lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;path&lt;/span&gt;, which will be followed by a &lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;profile&lt;/span&gt; (a circle in this case) to create the 3D arm. I created the path using the &lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;spline tool&lt;/span&gt; and eyeballing the general shape (it&apos;s really hard to measure curved objects, and I never intended to have an exact replica of my lamp).&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/lampModel/step3.png&quot; class=&quot;mb-p2 w-[50%]&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;After finishing the path, I used the &lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;sweep tool&lt;/span&gt; to generate a 3D model of the path using the off-cetered hole we sketched earlier as a profile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/lampModel/step4.png&quot; class=&quot;mb-p2 w-[50%]&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;The next step was undoubtedly the hardest part of the modeling process: the lampshade. I knew I wanted to do some kind of triangle, but I didn&apos;t know where to start. After taking a look at the different tools Fusion has, I decided to use the &lt;splan class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;revolve tool&lt;/splan&gt;. The revolve tool replicates a profile along an axis, which is exactly what I needed. I first created a point in the center of the end-part of the arm and created a perpendicular axis between that point and the arm (see image below, it&apos;s pretty hard to explain!). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/lampModel/step5.png&quot; class=&quot;mb-p2 w-[50%]&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;Using that axis, I created a plane which I used to create a sketch. The sketch is essentially a straight line with a &lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;75 degree angle&lt;/span&gt; and a length of &lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;70 mm&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/lampModel/step6.png&quot; class=&quot;mb-p2 w-[50%]&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;Finally, I used the revolve tool to replicate that sketch along the axis we created earlier. I used a &lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;360 degree angle&lt;/span&gt; to make a full circle, and therefore have a closed lampshade. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/lampModel/finished.png&quot; class=&quot;mb-p2 w-[50%]&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-lg mb-[5%]&quot;&gt;If you want to take a look at the design, you can download the &lt;a href=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/stl/lamp-stl.stl&quot; class=&quot;link&quot;&gt;.stl file&lt;/a&gt; or the Fusion360 &lt;a href=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/stl/lamp-f3d.f3d&quot; class=&quot;link&quot;&gt;.f3d file&lt;/a&gt;, or you can interact with it below!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://icloud83866.autodesk360.com/shares/public/SHd38bfQT1fb47330c99418829d72994de6f?mode=embed&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;  frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;mb-p2&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-xl underline&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2)&lt;/strong&gt; Modeling a pencil sharpener&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;The second object I&apos;m going to model is a pencil sharpener. This time, I will try to replicate my real pencil sharpener as accurately as possible. That is why I&apos;m going to use a caliper, which I strongly encourage anyone who wants to accurately model something to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/sharpenerModel/caliper.jpg&quot; class=&quot;mb-p2 w-[50%]&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;After taking a few measurements (you will find the measurements bellow) I sketched a simple top-down view of the sharpener.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;mb-p2&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/sharpenerModel/measurement1.jpg&quot; class=&quot;inline-block mr-[3%] mb-[1%] w-[25%]&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/sharpenerModel/measurement2.jpg&quot; class=&quot;inline-block mr-[3%] mb-[1%] w-[25%]&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/sharpenerModel/measurement3.jpg&quot; class=&quot;inline-block mb-[1%] w-[25%]&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p class=&quot;inline-block text-center mr-[3%] w-[25%] hl&quot;&gt;32.5 mm&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p class=&quot;inline-block text-center mr-[3%] w-[25%] hl&quot;&gt;37.6 mm&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p class=&quot;inline-block text-center w-[25%] hl&quot;&gt;39.1 mm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/sharpenerModel/topdownsketch.png&quot; class=&quot;w-[35%]&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p italic text-right w-[35%]&quot;&gt;Top-down sketch&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;I then did the same thing from a side-view. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;mb-p2&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/sharpenerModel/measurement4.jpg&quot; class=&quot;inline-block mr-[3%] mb-[1%] w-[35%]&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/sharpenerModel/measurement5.jpg&quot; class=&quot;inline-block mr-[3%] mb-[1%] w-[35%]&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p class=&quot;inline-block text-center mr-[3%] w-[35%] hl&quot;&gt;21.47 mm ≈ 21.5 mm&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p class=&quot;inline-block text-center mr-[3%] w-[35%] hl&quot;&gt;25.69 mm ≈ 25.7 mm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/sharpenerModel/sidesketch.png&quot; class=&quot; inline-block w-[45%] mr-[5%]&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/sharpenerModel/step1.png&quot; class=&quot;inline-block w-[45%]&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p italic text-right w-[43%]&quot;&gt;Side sketch&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;Now that we have this basic sketch, we can begin to create more detailed lines in the two different sketches and then extrude them to create a 3D model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/sharpenerModel/modelingvideo.gif&quot; class=&quot;mb-p w-[75%]&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;We can then join the two ellipses we just created using the &lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;loft tool&lt;/span&gt;, which &lt;span class=&quot;italic&quot;&gt;&quot;creates a transitional shape shape between two or more sketch profiles or planar faces&quot;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/sharpenerModel/step2.png&quot; class=&quot;mb-p w-[50%]&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;I then went back to the back-side sketch and added two circles with the dimensions I got using the caliper&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/sharpenerModel/measurement6.jpg&quot; class=&quot;inline-block mr-[3%] mb-[1%] w-[35%]&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/sharpenerModel/measurement7.jpg&quot; class=&quot;inline-block mr-[3%] mb-[1%] w-[35%]&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p class=&quot;inline-block text-center mr-[3%] w-[35%] hl&quot;&gt;11.34 mm ≈ 11.3 mm&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p class=&quot;inline-block text-center mr-[3%] w-[35%] hl&quot;&gt;8.1 mm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/sharpenerModel/step3.png&quot; class=&quot;mb-p w-[50%]&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;To create the hole, I started by creating an offset plane from those two circles with a distance of &lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;15 mm&lt;/span&gt;. I created a sketch on that plane, projected the two circles we just created, and then created two new circles with an offset of &lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;-4 mm&lt;/span&gt; for the big circle and &lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;-2.5 mm&lt;/span&gt; for the smaller one. We can now use the same tool we used before, loft, to reproduce the same effect we used earlier, but this time to cut into our existing model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/sharpenerModel/step4.png&quot; class=&quot;mb-p w-[50%]&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;To make it look better, I used the &lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;fillet tool&lt;/span&gt; to round the edges and added a black material to the model. We could add even more detail to the ouside of the pencil sharpener (some lines and depth) but I don&apos;t think it is worth, given that we would re-use the tools used in this model and the previous one. You&apos;ll find an image of the finished version bellow, along with some links to download the file in case you want to use/modify the model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/sharpenerModel/finished.png&quot; class=&quot;mb-p2 w-[50%]&quot;&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-lg mb-[5%]&quot;&gt;If you want to take a look at the design, you can download the &lt;a href=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/stl/sharpener-stl.stl&quot; class=&quot;link&quot;&gt;.stl file&lt;/a&gt; or the Fusion360 &lt;a href=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/stl/sharpener-f3d.f3d&quot; class=&quot;link&quot;&gt;.f3d file&lt;/a&gt;, or you can interact with it below!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://icloud83866.autodesk360.com/shares/public/SHd38bfQT1fb47330c9966d561ffb5d2eae5?mode=embed&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;  frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">1) Modeling a lamp</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Laser cutting: visiting Paris with cardboard</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/phys_s12_blog/2023/06/24/week2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Laser cutting: visiting Paris with cardboard" /><published>2023-06-24T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-06-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/phys_s12_blog/2023/06/24/week2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/phys_s12_blog/2023/06/24/week2.html">&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-xl underline&quot;&gt;Concept&lt;/h2&gt; 
&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;Laser cutting is an extremely useful technique to cut simple materials, such as cardboard. This week, we learned how to operate a laser cutter and we were assigned to create a press-fit construction. To accomplish this, I decided to use a CAD software called Fusion360. I already had experience using it, and the only way to do parametric accurate modeling in the other software option, Blender, is by using the addon &lt;a class=&quot;link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cadsketcher.com/&quot;&gt;CAD Sketcher&lt;/a&gt;. CAD Sketcher is an extremely new tool, and while it is true it has a huge community supporting it, I don&apos;t think that it has enough features to be used in big projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;After choosing which software I was going to use, I modeled some simple press-fit squares to know how much material the laser burns when cutting through cardboard. This is called laser kerf. I found out that a good value for the laser kerf was &lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;0.8 mm&lt;/span&gt;, which is less than I expected it to be. This meant I had to make my press-fit joints smaller than I initially thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/pressfittest.jpg&quot; class=&quot;mb-[1%] inline-block max-h-[432px] w-[49%]&quot; alt=&quot;Picture of two press-fit cardboard squares&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/pressfittestmodel.png&quot; class=&quot;w-[49%] align-top inline-block&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;w-fit hl mb-p&quot;&gt;Click to download the &lt;a class=&quot;link&quot; href=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/stl/press-fit-stl.stl&quot;&gt;.STL File&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;As you can probably see in the joints, the cardboard is slightly bent, and I had to do some force to get them to fit together. While that can be good for long-lasting designs, it is not what I&apos;m looking for. After disassembling and assembling it a few times, the cardboard would probably break. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later on, I started thinking about what kind of press-fit &quot;structure&quot; I was going to create. At first, I thought about doing something like a puzzle, but then I decided to go for something much more unique: the Eiffel Tower. I looked up some sketches online and decided to start modeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-xl mt-[30px] underline&quot;&gt;Modeling&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;The first thing I did was to search online for a reference image. I don&apos;t intend the model to be identical to the real Eiffel Tower, but I do expect it to look alike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.wikihow.com/Draw-the-Eiffel-Tower&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;inline-block w-[50%] mb-p&quot; src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/eiffeltowersketch.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;I then began to think about how I could join the different parts of the structure. The best idea I came up with was to cut 4 separate &quot;legs&quot;, and then join all four of them using press-fit squares placed in between them. I used splines to model the legs, which made designing them really easy. You can see the layout of the design below. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/eiffeltowerlayout.png&quot; class=&quot;w-[50%] mb-p&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;w-fit hl mb-p2&quot;&gt;Click to download the &lt;a class=&quot;link&quot; href=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/stl/eiffel-tower-stl.stl&quot;&gt;.STL File&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-xl underline&quot;&gt;Laser Cutting&lt;/h2&gt; 

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;After finishing the design, I exported the sketch as a &lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;.dxf&lt;/span&gt; file and loaded it into the laser cutter&apos;s computer using an SD card. The next step was to send it to the actual laser cutter, and then finally, chose the point in space where it should start cutting (to avoid cutting outside the cardboard, which would be a pretty bad thing!). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/lasercutter.jpg&quot; class=&quot;w-[50%]&quot; alt=&quot;Picture of the laser cutting&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p italic text-right w-[50%]&quot;&gt;Picture of the laser cutter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;The moment I got the pieces out of the laser cutter, I realized that I should have made the design bigger. I designed the model to be &lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;22 cm&lt;/span&gt; tall, which I thought would be a good height, but I quickly realized that having small values means having tiny amounts of material near the joints. The joints are therefore quite fragile. Nevertheless, everything fitted perfectly and the design turned out exactly like I wanted it to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/eiffeltowerfinished.jpg&quot; class=&quot;w-[30%]&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p2 italic text-right w-[30%]&quot;&gt;Finished Eiffel Tower&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-xl underline&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By working on this project, I learned how to use a laser cutter, deepened my CAD skills, and &lt;span class=&quot;hl&quot;&gt;visited Paris&lt;/span&gt;! Next time, I will make larger designs and make sure there is enough material near the joints so the structure can be as strong as possible.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Concept Laser cutting is an extremely useful technique to cut simple materials, such as cardboard. This week, we learned how to operate a laser cutter and we were assigned to create a press-fit construction. To accomplish this, I decided to use a CAD software called Fusion360. I already had experience using it, and the only way to do parametric accurate modeling in the other software option, Blender, is by using the addon CAD Sketcher. CAD Sketcher is an extremely new tool, and while it is true it has a huge community supporting it, I don&apos;t think that it has enough features to be used in big projects. After choosing which software I was going to use, I modeled some simple press-fit squares to know how much material the laser burns when cutting through cardboard. This is called laser kerf. I found out that a good value for the laser kerf was 0.8 mm, which is less than I expected it to be. This meant I had to make my press-fit joints smaller than I initially thought.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Website creation and final project ideas</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/phys_s12_blog/2023/06/21/week1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Website creation and final project ideas" /><published>2023-06-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-06-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/phys_s12_blog/2023/06/21/week1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/phys_s12_blog/2023/06/21/week1.html">&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-xl underline&quot;&gt;Website technology&lt;/h2&gt; 
&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;This site was created with the help of a static site generator: &lt;strong&gt;Jekyll&lt;/strong&gt;. Static site generators are really useful when content looks similar, which is exactly the case of a blog. That is why I decided to use Jekyll for this project. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;To style the site, I&apos;m using &lt;a href=&quot;https://tailwindcss.com&quot; class=&quot;link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;TailwindCSS&lt;/a&gt;, which a css framework that is extremely useful for rapidly building a good-looking website. It works pretty much like a modern version of bootstrap. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;mb-p&quot;&gt;I think that the most interesting development choice of this project is using &lt;strong&gt;Github Actions&lt;/strong&gt; to compile and deploy the website. I had never used Github Actions, but there are many useful ressources online to learn how to use them. This Github feature allows you to quickly setupt actions to do things such as, in this case, automate the Jekyll build of my website. You&apos;ll find bellow a picture of what an &quot;action&quot; looks like. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/githubactions.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of a Github Action&quot;&gt;


&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-xl mt-[30px] underline&quot;&gt;Final Project Idea #1&lt;/h2&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;My first idea for the final project is to design a &lt;strong&gt;thrust vector control (TVC) &lt;/strong&gt; mount for model rockets. TVC allows rockets to change the direction of its thrust, and therefore its flight trajectory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;mb-p link&quot; href=&quot;https://bps.space/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/tvcexample.jpg&quot; class=&quot;inline&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;p class=&quot;text-sm&quot;&gt;3D model of a TVC mount made by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/@BPSspace&quot; class=&quot;link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;bps.space&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To achieve a successfull project, I would need to succesfully develop a gimbal capable of holding a model rocket thruster, and a flight computer capable of detecting the orientation of the rocket (and therefore corret the trajectory).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-xl mt-[30px] underline&quot;&gt;Final Project Idea #2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My second final project idea is to design and build a &lt;strong&gt;3D printed RC car&lt;/strong&gt;. This project would require a lot of material testing (to make sure the different parts of the car are strong enough to sustain high speeds), and a lot of research to find the right components. 
    That is I&apos;m more inclined to pursue my first idea, which would only require simple components (such as servos).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/phys_s12_blog/assets/images/rccarexample.jpg&quot; class=&quot;inline mt-5&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;text-sm&quot;&gt;Example of a 3d printed car made by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r2UDc4A8huY&quot; class=&quot;link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Engineering Nonsense&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Website technology This site was created with the help of a static site generator: Jekyll. Static site generators are really useful when content looks similar, which is exactly the case of a blog. That is why I decided to use Jekyll for this project. To style the site, I&apos;m using TailwindCSS, which a css framework that is extremely useful for rapidly building a good-looking website. It works pretty much like a modern version of bootstrap. I think that the most interesting development choice of this project is using Github Actions to compile and deploy the website. I had never used Github Actions, but there are many useful ressources online to learn how to use them. This Github feature allows you to quickly setupt actions to do things such as, in this case, automate the Jekyll build of my website. You&apos;ll find bellow a picture of what an &quot;action&quot; looks like.</summary></entry></feed>